Hello friends, welcome to ManSamvad.
I am Heena Shah and in today's video,
we will talk about how to select your
accommodation in various European destinations.
Yes, we have always chosen AirBnB for our
various European trips, that means apartments.
And today I will share various insider tips
with you on how I select these apartments.
Along with this, I will tell you in
more detail about our mistakes so that you
do not repeat the mistakes we have made.
So let's say you have booked your flights,
you have also decided your entire itinerary.
Now it is very important to select an
accommodation because when you give your itinerary for
Schengen visa, you will have to book an
accommodation.
But when you select the final accommodation, you
have to listen carefully to what all things
you will keep in mind.
When I have to book an apartment, I
start shortlisting.
So let's say I am looking for apartments
in Milan or I am looking for apartments
in Lucerne.
So I will start shortlisting the apartments on
the website.
I prefer airbnb.com.
So when I start shortlisting, if all the
filters you have to apply match your requirements
and you have shortlisted a few apartments, then
you definitely have to check the distance of
those apartments.
You have to check the price because that
will be the first criteria that whether it
is sitting in our budget or not.
If there is a little plus or minus,
then it is fine.
But if it is out of budget, then
obviously you will have to leave that apartment
and choose an apartment that is in your
budget.
What are the criteria that I keep in
mind while shortlisting?
First of all is rating.
Yes, I select the rating which is more
than 4.5 out of 5.
Nothing less than 4.5 because you never
know what has gone wrong in that apartment.
So once this filter is applied more than
4.5, then you will get to know
what is left for you to select.
After that, amenities.
Yes, the first amenity in my filters will
be having a kitchen.
Having a gas stove, microwave, refrigerator in the
kitchen is very important for me.
So as a family, when we travel, I
prefer cooking my own meals in the kitchen.
So when all these facilities are there, they
are very helpful to me.
So according to you, you can select which
amenities you want.
If you are at the same place for
a long time, then maybe you will find
the washing machine facility useful.
And not to forget heater.
If we are going to colder places, then
it is very important to have a heater.
And if you go to Europe in the
month of July-August, then it is very
hot there.
So in that case, it is very important
to have an AC.
You will still get a heater because these
are cold countries.
But since these are cold countries, they have
not installed an AC before.
Now, due to climate change in the last
few years, the heat has increased a lot.
So still few places have ACs and most
of the places might just have a table
fan.
The ceiling fan is still in very few
places.
So see to it that in which month
you are going, whether you need an AC
or not.
Check in the list of amenities.
Again, one more thing, very very important.
If this apartment is in a building and
on a higher floor, then what will you
need?
Yes, lift, elevator.
Because you are not going to climb up
the stairs with such heavy baggage.
That will be very very uncomfortable.
This has happened with us.
And I am telling you all these points
after suffering something or the other in every
accommodation.
In our first trip to Paris, our first
apartment was on the fourth floor.
And in the old building of Paris, the
spiral wooden stairs, we had kept our baggage
up to four floors.
So we have learnt a lot from our
mistakes.
I don't want you all to make such
So you can see in the listing whether
elevator or lift is available or not.
Very very important.
Similarly, whatever amenities you need, if you need
Wi-Fi.
And what we have, because when we are
out, we do depend a lot on Wi
-Fi.
So see to it that Wi-Fi is
in your listing.
But it happens that Wi-Fi is not
provided.
So all these small things are there in
the bathroom.
What amenities are there or not?
What do I mean by amenities?
So few countries, like when I was booking
recently for our last trip.
So when we were booking in Ayozta, NSE,
all these places.
Here, the normal essentials like your shower gel,
like bath linen.
All these things are not included.
At times you have to pay extra for
such basic amenities also.
So be very very sure when you see
the listing.
What are the essentials included in it and
what are not included.
Because when we reached NSE, we had to
go to the supermarket and buy shower gel.
So what happens is generally when we travel.
All these things are available in most of
the apartments.
So it never happens that they are not
there.
And unfortunately, at this time in my travel
kit, I forgot to take any shower gel.
So it does happen.
Be sure to check the amenities carefully.
Last but not the least.
In this list is that whenever you finalize
any booking.
So you have to take the code of
the door of the apartment from the host.
Or the main door of the building outside
the apartment.
You have to put a code of that.
You know 4 digit, 8 digit, whatever it
is.
So take that code properly.
Most of the hosts whose rating is above
4.5. They themselves will provide you the
full detail.
In fact, a lot of hosts send you
the whole photo and video on messaging.
So you can easily find the apartment.
And you can easily find their door.
In this way, they send you photographs or
videos.
But sometimes it happens that they forgot to
send the code.
Or there is some miscommunication or communication mismatch.
So be careful when you leave here for
your trip.
So whatever is your first accommodation.
So check with the host how to reach
that accommodation.
Which street, which number you have to go.
And you have to put the code twice.
First, you have to put the code in
the main building.
And then many a times even their own
door also has a code.
So be careful to take those codes properly.
I am saying this because when we went
to Denmark.
We reached midnight.
Almost 12 o'clock.
And it so happened that the host did
not give his house number properly.
And the street we reached.
All the houses were the same.
When all the houses were the same, we
were very confused.
How to call them at midnight 12 o
'clock.
Whether to do it or not.
And in which house should we go.
We were not getting any idea.
Then we took a chance.
A house which seemed to be the host's
house from this photo.
We went inside that house.
After going inside, there was our room upstairs.
In the whole house, on the first floor.
She was renting out rooms.
So this was a shared apartment.
Initially, sometimes we used to take shared apartments.
And then we went upstairs.
There were 4-5 rooms.
So I think she allotted all the guests.
And after one room, there was a chit
on the door.
And that chit again was not Danish.
So we translated it standing there.
After reading it, we came to know that
this is our room.
And we have to check in here.
So even a small mistake.
Even a small detail.
If you forget to take it.
Then you can face a lot of trouble.
So these are small things.
But be careful.
That you take all the details from your
host.
Next.
It has also happened with us.
That we reached.
Our first trip to Paris.
10 years back.
The location that the host had written.
We reached there with the baggage.
We flew directly from India to Paris.
So you know the host.
No key instructions.
No details of anything.
And we were trying to contact the host.
On his phone.
And the phone was not reachable.
Another one more thing we noticed.
Since this was my first international Europe trip.
And this was the first time I was.
Experiencing booking Airbnbs.
So I didn't know that before booking me.
What is the area like?
I should check it.
I made a big mistake there.
So that area.
Was a very bad area.
So it was a complete red light area.
And unfortunately.
We had just booked there.
And moreover the host did not pick up
the phone.
Now fortunately.
We had a friend with us.
Who came to take us to the airport.
She was staying in Paris.
So fortunately she was there with us.
She offered you to come to my house.
She was herself sharing the accommodation.
With three other people.
But she invited us to her place.
Because it was very expensive in Europe.
But we took a cab.
From that place to her house.
So we spent a lot of money in
Europe.
And thankfully she hosted us.
We had to stay for one night.
She hosted us for that night.
So be sure.
Whenever you book.
Take care of all the small details.
Of course after checking the amenities.
Pictures.
You know it comes along with amenities.
Whatever pictures the host has uploaded.
Look at the pictures properly.
If you see any discrepancy.
Then clear it with the host.
And if there are very few pictures.
Then please don't go for that apartment.
And if there are no pictures of the
bathroom.
Then also don't go for that apartment.
See to it that all the things.
Bedroom, living room, kitchen, bathroom.
All the pictures of the place.
Have been shown to you clearly.
And don't forget to read the reviews.
Especially the latest reviews.
Read them definitely.
And obviously the reviews of the star rating.
I read them first.
So that all the guests.
Give this host a star rating.
Many guests mostly write in the reviews.
How much distance is this apartment.
How much distance is the supermarket below.
How is the communication with the host.
So you get a lot of confidence from
that.
Whether I should book this apartment or not.
Location.
I personally select the location.
So that I don't get too expensive.
And I don't have to go too far.
So what do I mean by that.
I mean to say.
If you select any location near the central
station.
Then the accommodation can be very expensive for
you.
So since we buy city pass.
In which the fee of the city is
included.
So what I prefer.
I select it from a little distance from
the central station.
So that my cost can be very low.
And next.
I select accommodation in this way.
In which anywhere.
Bus, metro, tram stop.
Near my apartment.
So what happens is when I take the
baggage.
So I don't have to walk a lot.
So as soon as I am out of
the metro tram or bus.
The apartment comes in a few meters.
So in Airbnb or any apartment.
They don't give you that final address.
Then how do I know.
How far is my distance.
Personally what I do.
I open Google Maps.
And when I check the location in Airbnb.
So if there is any famous restaurant nearby.
Or if there is any shop.
I see its name.
And then I put the name of that
shop on Google Maps.
So that I know approximately.
How far is this apartment from the central
station.
And how will I be able to travel.
So this gives me a fair bit idea.
How can I finalize my accommodation.
So if you.
Got a list.
That I am interested in all these apartments.
So you can see its distance.
How far is it from the central station.
So once you check the distance.
You will get a fair bit idea.
How far you will have to travel.
Distance from the central station.
Also distance from the old city.
And the main square.
Where you have to go for a lot
of sightseeing.
You definitely check these two things.
And then you will get confidence.
That yes this is the apartment.
I get finalized.
Then you check the communication with the host.
If you have messaged the host.
And he is taking a lot of time.
Like more than 24 hours to reply to
you.
Then for me that's a red flag.
I will not go for that host.
Because if I have already reached the place.
The location.
And I am trying to communicate something with
the host.
And if that person is not replying.
Then it is of no use to me.
So you see this.
How he is replying in 1 hour, 2
hours, 4 hours.
Because the way he is replying now.
In the same way.
If you have reached there later.
And you are having some trouble.
So in the same way he can reply
to you quickly.
So these are very fine tips.
Very very small points.
That you need to be careful.
While selecting your accommodation.
Next in many cities.
There is also a city tax.
And many times this city tax.
The host will tell you.
That in Milan.
Whatever city tax was of the people.
We gave it to them in cash.
And that is fine.
Because the city does charge.
And it is clearly written on the airbnb
site.
Also cleaning fees.
Be very sure to figure out.
Are cleaning fees included or separately chargeable.
So depending on that.
The overall cost of your apartment.
It can be less or more.
Mostly when we select apartments.
Cleaning fees are included.
But it is always wise to check.
If it can be changed.
So these things are.
Few things which you have to be.
Very very careful of.
Otherwise for us.
Booking apartments has been a boon.
In every which ways.
Like you know for many trips.
It so happens that there is a washing
machine facility.
So most of my clothes are washed there
itself.
When I come back.
I have all washed clothes in my bag.
I don't have to do the laundry after
coming back.
So about kitchen as I told you.
I always prefer using the kitchen.
Because it's much much bigger than a hotel
room.
So we prefer you know.
Since we are three of us.
To use the whole space.
It feels good like a home.
You know many hosts are like this.
Who keep a small snack or something.
And most of the hosts.
Have been very nice to us.
We never got a complaint from any host.
Except for the first one in Paris.
Which was not available itself.
And because he was not there.
We immediately complained on airbnb.
And the entire amount.
We got a refund.
Not only that much amount.
In fact some extra compensation.
He also refunded us.
So there was no issues at all.
There has been no issues at all till
date.
Most of the hosts have been very kind.
Very accommodating.
Very helpful.
Because we as guests also.
Have been very you know.
Cleanliness oriented.
The way we get clean apartments.
So while leaving.
That's why our host also gives you reviews.
If you check.
Whatever reviews we get.
We get very excellent reviews.
And these reviews are very useful.
Because next time.
If you send a request to any host.
That I want to book your apartment.
They can read your reviews.
And if earlier reviews are very good.
They immediately agree.
Yes please go ahead and book my apartment.
So be careful.
That as a guest.
The host also reviews you.
So you don't have to worry.
You have to wash your dishes.
And keep them clean.
And if you stay for 2-3 days.
Then you don't have to do much cleaning.
But see to it.
That you don't throw anything here and there.
Mostly see to it.
Give the apartment back.
In the condition that you have received.
Then it's always a win-win situation.
So I hope this video was helpful to
you.
To understand how to book an apartment.
For your trips.
Yes I have noticed one thing.
In case you think my videos are very
long.
And I should make the duration shorter.
Then please mention in the comments.
That I should make the duration of the
videos short.
So what I will do is.
That I will publish the video in parts.
Apart from that.
If you want videos on any other topic.
Then please mention in the comments.
That what other topics should I make videos
on.
So I hope this video will help you.
To choose the correct accommodation.
For your upcoming trip.
Happy travels.
Thank you so much. (Transcribed by TurboScribe.ai.)